Excellent. All right. So, I'm going to
quickly run through some slides kind of
uh these were sort of thrown in. Um,
funny enough, I am here representing
continue and today's my first day at the
job. So, yeah. Right. That's great. So,
my name is Brian Douglas. I go by
Douggee. Uh, I'm Bucky on GitHub. I
actually used to work at this company.
Um, like upstairs and downstairs. I
didn't have a desk. Uh, worked here for
almost 5 years. Uh Anthony who's
delivering the pizza back there. Hung
out with all those guys all the time. So
um can ask questions about GitHub later,
but I'm here to talk about continue. Um
who uses AI coding assistants to
generate code? Your boss is not here, so
you can put your hand up really high all
the time. What is it like 80% of your
code generated with AI at this point?
Yeah. Cool. So I want to talk about
writing rules. uh AI generated code can
sometimes be you know it needs some some
strict rules sometimes could be loose
rules. Um I I wrote the tweet on Friday
because I kept seeing a bunch of folks
that I I sort of looked up to in the co
coding industry our industry talk about
how AI is kind of ruining all the good
things and the bad things. Um you bet
this actually came from a blog post on
the left called co-pilot delusion. Um
it's an okay blog post but I thought
that quote was really cool. Um, I
thought it was like it kind of really
spoke to me because I wanted to really
think about maybe we're just using it
wrong. You guys remember like Steve
Jobs, you're holding it wrong with the
iPhone. Um, and then the right post is
actually from Steve Clabnik uh who's
like famous for Rust and Ruby and Rails.
Um, that was like my coming up age of uh
I used to read Steve's blog post all the
time. Uh, but what I'm getting at is
like I've got a journey. I kind of
mentioned I used to work at GitHub. Uh,
I actually started writing code
professionally about 12 years ago. I was
getting my MBA, got a finance degree,
was doing sales, then learned how to
code, moved out here for a job, and my
first language was actually Ruby. Uh,
and funny enough, this guy is part of
the reason why I write I wrote Ruby
code, and I ended up getting up to to
GitHub. You guys know this guy, Uncle
Bob. He's been on X, the the Twitter,
formerly known as Twitter. He does like
these daily rants in his robe for some
reason. I didn't even know what this
was. I don't watch videos on X anymore
because they're like X rated. um
including this one. Uh but actually the
he has a lot of like strong thoughts
around programming and clean code. He
wrote a book about clean code and it got
me thinking like what if we could write
code with agents but keep them in a way
that could have structure and write code
that's predictively going to be good. Um
so back when I first learned how to code
about 12 years ago, I I learned Ruby and
then the next week I went to this code
retreat. Uh I'm from Tampa, Florida. So
Bob, Uncle Bob actually had ETHlight was
the place he worked at. The consultancy
had an office in Tampa and Chicago and I
just had the luck out that I lived there
and they would teach you how to build
this little program called the game of
life. Anybody built game of life?
Conways game of life. It's a cool little
program writing different languages. Uh
and this is literally how I learned Ruby
that weekend, which is like build that
thing. So I kind of just wanted to spend
the rest of time talking through a demo
in my VS Code. Sorry that's ghosty. Uh,
so this is my VS Code. Uh, and then I
want to talk about this concept that I I
heard Nate talk about last week called
spec driven development. It's the idea
of having like you can do a cool little
prompt. And I'm going to open up the uh
the little side chat. So this is
continue. Uh, and I'm going to just use
let's use a
llama because I kind of I want this not
to work. So I'm gonna use a small
parameter and say implement the game of
life based on the spec. So the game of
life basically you've got all these
squares and if like two item two alive
squares are next to each other it kills
the one that you're looking at and then
like if there's three then like anyway
I'll show you what it looks basically
what I just showed you. It just has like
a nice little command line interface. So
I'm just going to
basically try to vibe this thing but I'm
actually going to chat with it first. So
we got this option here um option to
either edit the code or chat with it.
But I want to implement the game of life
uh using the
spec MD. So probably something you
familiar you can use some context make
it make the agent or sorry the um coding
assistant aware of what you're asking.
And I'm just going to not even try hard.
I'm just going to go ahead and just do
that and see what happens. Um and the
cool thing about this is I'm using Llama
local uh using O Lama. It's built in
into my machine. I've already installed
it locally. Um, raise your hand if any
you guys are using code assistants but
are using anyone using Olama for
decoding assistant or tried it once. Got
to try it once. All right, there we go.
Um, so it's going to implement basically
the game of life uh in Ruby code. So,
pretty straightforward. I've already
written out the spec. It's going to be
directly from the PDF you get from the
website. Uh, and it's going to
eventually, and because it's my local
machine, this M4 Pro, not a max, 16
gigabytes. It's going to take some
time, but I will go ahead and trust that
this is going to be working soon. Let me
go back to my demo. Um, so I guess what
I wanted to talk about spectriven
development and also test-driven
development is you can really just write
some guard rails up front to make sure
that your agent is going to get the
stuff that you want it to do. And I
think what I'm getting out with Uncle
Bob is like there are best practices
that exist in coding. And I think if
anybody's been coding for, you know,
longer than five years, before the AI
revolution, we used to do this. Uh, and
then in the last six months, we stopped
because we could vibe it. Uh, well, I
stopped because I could vibe code it.
So, I speak for myself. Um, so I've got
my spec, but I've also want to write
test. And testing is actually something
I started testing legitimately, no pun
intended, uh, two months ago. I thought,
oh, if I could get agent, can I get the
agent to write test first? Uh, so the
thing I'm gonna talk through, so like it
did implement this. If I wanted to go
ahead and create that file, I won't, but
I only have 15 minutes. So, uh, I'm
going to just forget that that even
happened. Uh, and I'm going to switch to
a faster model. Um, and the other thing
I'm going to do is I'm going to add, uh,
get stash apply. Uh, and the one Oh,
sorry. The one thing I was going to show
is I do have rules. So, I did have one
rule, which is basically write clean and
readable Ruby code. I don't have time to
go break down Ruby code and teach you
all the ins and outs on you know the
Ruby methodology. Uh but I did have a
bunch of other rules that I wanted to
apply. Uh and the cool thing about this
is these rules are taken directly from
places I learned how to code from. So if
I go to uh that's
me if I go to this these two books. So I
read these books like pretty much back
to front cover to cover. I've read
similar books in Go, but clean Ruby,
clean code, pragmatic programmer, like
all this type of stuff is how you kind
of learn the basics. And I think we have
an opportunity to teach our agents the
same stuff that we should be teaching.
And I think when we think about
foundational models, maybe we get this
for free, but a lot of times you don't
have access to like a full-on cloud for
like maybe you're using Gemma, maybe you
have a local model for your work that
you have to use because your boss said
to uh this gives you an opportunity to
add rules and add not even rules for
you, but rules you could share across
teams as well. So I've got like write
clean code, but also write tests using
TDD. So, uh, what I wanted to actually
test out real quick, um, I'm going to
switch to agent mode, and I'm going to
say
implement
[Music]
the
game. Typing is hard. Okay. life uh
using the spec RB in a
uh
what's I probably should have created
this file to keep it more constrained
but let's see if it can uh create a game
RB ideally you probably have a longer
prompt keep more constraint you know
talk to like a junior programmer
um but let's see what
happens and what it's going to basically
use all these rules to basically have
constraints on things like lines
how long method should be. If you've if
you've read uh read any of these books,
it's going to have all this context on
how to write clean Ruby code. Um, so
that's going to go ahead and run. And
I'm going to run through the rest of my
slides real quick. Uh, so the one thing
I wanted to point out is what I was
actually really impressed at when I was
talking to continue about joining is
continue really exists for amplifying
devs and not automating devs. So I know
like Satcha stood on stage at Build and
was like, "Hey, remember pair
programming?" pure programming. Uh, and
I think actually it it sounds silly, but
I think actually a really good way to
think about it. I was actually at GitHub
when Copilot launched and it was all
about co-pilots. It was about assisting.
It was about having a junior programmer
along for the ride. And I think what we
could do is we can level up these junior
programmers to eventually become senior
uh and senior agents. And I think the
one thing we should all be thinking
about is like what legitimately junior
programmers like what are we doing for
them moving forward? And I think what we
end up doing for them is providing rules
and guardrails to accelerate their
development and not leave them out in
the out in the dust. Um so cool about
this with continue. You can create and
share these rules. You can create
assistance. You can reuse models across
teams. You can create a team account and
it gives you an opportunity to have a a
sort of a full experience to sort of
meet everyone at the same level. So
um I wasn't planning on sharing slides.
I don't know why people are taking
pictures of it but should I smile? Um,
but yeah, let's take a look at uh where
we're at. Uh, cool thing about continue
is you got to hit a continue button if
you don't auto accept those changes. Uh,
but one thing I'm going to just point
out is like I do have the game of life
written in code. It's going to be clean
Ruby. I didn't run the last one because
I tested this all day and it always
fails the first time because I didn't
have enough rules to write good Ruby
code. Um, and when I use like a local
smaller parameter model, it always fails
because I don't know anybody training
models on Ruby code. That's what I
thought. So, uh, it's going to run the
game of life. It's going to run it.
Cool. It's going to run it in the
prompt, too. So, you kind of saw it for
a second. I could run it again down here
if I if I needed to. Uh, but the other
thing I wanted to point out is I could
also say based on my rules, uh, please
implement
test
nagame.test.rb. So, we'll see if that
happens and then I will look around if
anybody has any questions.
Nope.
Oh, question right here.
Okay, so the first model was run
locally. I did cheat a little bit and
this one's actually hosted on continue.
Uh, so I'll open up my
uh, it's actually running. I think I
have a config.
Sorry, I don't want to break the agent,
but I'll show you once the agent's
complete. But essentially, I have a
token, a anthropic token that's pointed
that I've hosted on a server. Uh, and
it's running that. So, obviously, you
can't run Claude uh local on your
machine. It's one, it's too big, but
also it's not accessible. It's well,
they don't let
you. Any other
questions? Oh, there we go. We got some
test. And I can assure you these are
these are pretty good tests as
well. Let's see if it gets me a
description and I can run
this. Cool. Yep. So it's going to run
all the tests. I've got oh four failures
and that's TDD for you. So test driven
development. You get failures and you go
and fix them. Uh funny enough, I was
actually expecting the test to be
written first. So I've got to I've got
to go slap the agent and tell it to
write tests uh in all caps. Um but when
I was testing this earlier, it actually
was writing the test first. Uh, but I
did want to go ahead and show ruby
game.rb. Uh, and you can kind of see the
the
pattern. That's interesting. It didn't
imp anyway. That's I I didn't have a lot
of um rules on how to write the game of
life. Uh, but it it earlier today was
actually writing it much better and uh I
think I'm gonna How much time do I have?
Can I just regenerate this entire
project again? Few minutes. I have a few
minutes. All right, let's do it.
Oh man, let's see an agent go this fast.
I'm just
kidding. It's like the the get commands
you um you know what I think what
uh what I'll do is uh I'll help it cheat
a little bit and I'll give it the files
so we can skip some
steps. And I remember what the prompt I
did which is uh implement implementment
the
spec in
game make it visually interesting. So
that was the keyword I was doing earlier
today and I forgot to do
that. Uh so hopefully it'll generate a
visually interesting one instead of this
like uh
screenshots. Uh but I was actually so I
was writing some code for my last job
and I was writing a bunch of Ruby code
and I haven't written Ruby code like
professionally since probably 2016. Um I
sort of like dabbled while at GitHub
doing a bunch of side things and poking
at the Rails monolith. Um but in reality
I just wasn't caught up to speed on what
change in Ruby and like how to write
Ruby code today. Um, so the cool thing
about this is I was able to catch up
pretty quickly by this taking the PDF of
my clean Ruby book and saying generate
rules. Um, and I was using perplexity
for that. Like you could do that in a
chatbt or whatnot. Um, so what I'm
pointing out the idea and I know there's
like certain uh repos where folks share
rules um across like directories uh is
potentially have a community of folks
sharing rules uh specifically for their
community uh and eventually teams. So if
anybody wants to talk about that, I'd
love to chat about that. um
later. Cool. We got
implementation. It's got a lot of googly
goop. Let's go ahead and run
that. Oh, it didn't
print. Add a print to the bottom of the
file. That's I think that would be
obvious.
Um, all right. Last last one and then I
will give it up to the next
speaker. Now it's getting
slower. All right, I guess there's going
to have to be trust me,
bro. I swear it worked this morning.
All right. Thanks so much. I'm B Doggy
and Oh, sorry. What was the question?
Did I save the file?
Oh, I'm the junior.
Okay, that's the junior right there. It
did. It It did exactly what I said.
Print. That's uh that's amazing. It's
got jokes. All right. Well, thanks so
much. It's just going to keep
generating.